Sean Teare

4073 North Course Dr ♦ Charlotte, NC 28277 ♦ (910) 200-4802 ♦ steare573@gmail.com ♦ https://github.com/steare573

PROFILE

Full-stack software engineer specializing in Javascript, ReactJS and Redux. Articulate communicator with experience interacting with business leadership and managing engineers. Productive and comfortable in both team-based and self-managed environments. Passionate about real-time web applications, innovations in Javascript, design patterns, and open source technology.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Full-Stack Web Application Development, SOA Design and Implementation, Real-time Web Applications w/ Websockets, Unit Testing and Continuous Integration, Object-Oriented, Event-Driven, and System Architecture, Data Analytics Tools

TOOLS

JavaScript, Node.js, ReactJS, Flux, Redux, AngularJS, CommonJS, PHP, MySQL, Silex, Symfony2, Java, OSX/Linux, Git, Redis, Memcached, MongoDB, RabbitMQ, NSQ, Grunt, Gulp, Apache, PHPUnit, Mocha, Selenium, Jira, Stash, Bamboo

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Red Ventures Charlotte, North Carolina

Director of Software Engineering

January 2016 - Present

- Managed a team of 7 engineers to develop and maintain CRM, front-end marketing assets, product management systems, and order placement integrations with some of our largest partners, including Verizon and American Express.
- Assisted in resource allocation, applying technical governance standards, and making architectural decisions affecting all of our business partnerships as well as internal products.
- Spearheaded an initiative to provide continuous learning opportunities to our team of 100+ software engineers including topics on ReactJS., Flux, Redux, CommonJS, Webpack, Mocha, React Perf/Dev Tools, and the ReactJS ecosystem. Played a key role in launching, organizing, and implementing a program for engineers to drive creative and influential side-projects that provide both value to the business and development opportunities for our engineering team.

Senior Software Engineer - Internal Product Development

January 2014 - December 2015

- Integrated with Facebook Messenger using Facebook's alpha live chat Node.js client plugging it into our existing live chat platform via Redis and NSQ. Developed a new front-end UI for agents to interface with Messenger customers utilizing websockets, ReactJS, Redux, and Immutable.js.
- Developed features and maintained all components of real-time chat application that included customer-facing chat client on
 partner marketing sites, agent interface for handling multiple customer chats, back-end servers for socket event handling and chat
 routing to agents, RESTful web services for CRM integration, and message queuing system for backend communication using
 Node.js, AngularJS, ReactJS PHP, Silex, Redis, NSQ, and MongoDB.
- Designed, architected, and implemented a modular, socket-based, real-time sales platform that provided CRM system, phone
 system integration, agent workflow management system, and sales platform used by hundreds of sales agents using Node.js,
 ReactJS w/ Flux, RabbitMQ, and Redis as core architecture components.
- Developed API framework for development of RESTful web services with a data access layer providing extremely flexible system for partner level functionality overrides and configuration using primarily Express, Node.js, PHP, Silex, and MySQL.

Lead Software Engineer - Security Cluster

February 2011 - December 2014

- Managed team of developers in development and maintenance of sales platform, tools, API integrations and analytics
 visualization supporting several partner relationships including ADT, LifeShield Security, and LifeLock generating over \$30 million
 in revenue.
- Interacted with business leadership to pitch, plan, and implement several long-term projects including major refactoring of legacy systems and disaster recovery system for partner outages resulting in huge cost savings.
- Launched full technology stack for integration with multiple national brand partners including SOAP API integration, sales platform for agent orders, transactional database schema design, data analytics tools, and financial reconciliation processes using PHP, MySQL, and JavaScript.

Junior Web Developer

December 2009 - January 2011

- Developed dynamic data analysis tools and real-time dashboards for sales agents and business analysts.
- Created administrative tool suite and split-testing framework for scripting and sales platform management.
- Added features to sales platform used by 50+ users primarily using PHP, MySQL, and JavaScript.

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Science, Computer Science, 2009 University of North Carolina at Wilmington - Wilmington, NC 3.92 GPA